Guide to the Yale University Corporation Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Meeting minutes and subject files, 1975-1979, 1984; Accession 1991-A-027
  - Provost's Advisory Committee on Retirement, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Important Pending Litigation, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Inquiries Regarding Files of Employees and Students, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Annual Report on Affirmative Action, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Institutional Policies Committee, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Special Greetings, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 43 - 45)
  - Africa, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Minutes of the Corporation, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Minutes of the Corporation, 1978 April (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Minutes, 1978 January (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Corporation, University, and Church records, circa 1714-1899; Accession 1993-A-083
  The materials are open for research. Duplication of materials requires repository approval due to fragility.
  Arrangement
  The material is arranged chronologically.
  - An Extract from a Book Entitled "The Antient and Present State of the University of Oxford,'' by John Ayliffe, L.L.D, 1714 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - ALS D. Turner to Thomas Clap, 1722 September 24 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Extract from a Journal Regarding Provision of a Resident Rector, 1723 October (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Donation of the Reverend Isaac Watts, D.D. of London to Yale College Library, 1730 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - General Assembly Regarding Acreage, 1732 October 12 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Reckoning of College Accounts," Corporation, 1738 August 22 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Draft of a letter to Isaac Watts, thanking him for his gift to the College, New Haven, 1738 November 15 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - General Assembly Regarding Acreage, 1740 October (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Oaths of Allegiance Prescribed in the College Charter, Thomas Clap and Fellows, 1745 June (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Announcement of Meeting to Col. Livingston, 1745/1746 January 27 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Petition the General Assembly from President Clap (copy) Regarding Repairs to the College; Lists of Materials (copies), 1746/1747 January 28, 1751-1752 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - AL Copy From Yale College to the Towns of Kent, Cornwall, Canaan and Goshen Regarding Yale Farms, 1747 September 27 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Corporation Votes, 1753 November 21 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Thomas Clap, ALS to Naphtali Daggett, 1755 March 20 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - The Connecticut Gazette, 1755 October 18 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Oath of Fellow Ashbel Woodbridge, 1755 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Meetings of the First Society, 1756 January 12, 26 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Daggett, Naphtali: The Confession of Faith at his Installment as Professor, 1756 March 4 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Corporation Meeting, 1756 March 4 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Corporation Meeting (Copy), 1756 March 4 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Hobart, Noah: ALS to Jared Eliot, Against his resignation from the Yale Corporation, 1756 Sep28 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Yale College Church Papers, Relating to Its Establishment and Protests Against, 1756, 1757, 1781? (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Church Petition and Covenant to the President and Fellows of Yale College, 1756-1757? (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Burr, Aaron: ALS to Naphtali Daggett, 1757 May 10 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Petition to the General Assembly by Jared Eliot and Thomas Ruggles, 1758 May 8 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Confession of Wagering by David Lee; Petition by David Lee, 1758 September 4 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Oath of Fellow Moses Dickinson, 1758 December 6 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Regarding to "The Smallness Difficulties," and the "Eating of Common", 1761 July 21 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Oath of the Steward Phillip Dagget (Baller), 1762 August 25 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Petition to the General Assembly, 1763 March 10 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - President Clap's Reply to the Memorial for a Visitation of Yale College, 1763 May (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Memorial to the General Assembly at Hartford, 1763? (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - ALS Eleazar Wheelock to the Corporation Regarding sending Youths with Indians to Remote Indian Tribes, circa 1763 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Regarding the Annual Grant from the Colony: Vote of the Corporation, 1765 September (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Oaths of Allegiance Prescribed in the College Charter, circa 1765 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Cash Book of the Treasurer of The Church in Yale College, 1765-1771 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Memorandum Regarding Agreement of Kent Firm with Thomas Clap Regarding Lottery to Build the New College, 1766 October 24 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Grant by the General Assembly of the Colony of Connecticut to Yale College from Import Duties on Rum, 1766 October (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - List of Persons Who Desire Printed Copies of the Installation Sermon of President Daggett, 1766? (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - The Literary Character of President Clap, ALS Professor Daggett, Newport, And Photostat of ALS to Ezra Stiles Asking Regarding Character of N. Daggett, 1767 July 28 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Instructions Given by President Clap and the Fellows to Edward Eells, 1767 October 15 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Memorial to the General Assembly from the President and Fellows, 1767 October 18 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Grant by the General Assembly of the Colony of Connecticut to Yale College from Import Duties on Rum, 1767 October (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Grant by the General Assembly of the Colony of Connecticut to Yale College from Import Duties on Rum, 1768 October (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - John Witherspoon: Letter to President Daggett, 1768 November 24 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Grant by the General Assembly of the Colony of Connecticut to Yale College from Import Duties on Rum, 1769 October (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Corporation Judgment Against James Nichols, 1771 September 11 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Naphtali Daggett, ALS to Benjamin Lord, 1772 July 6 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Samuel Locke, AN (ALS?) to Naphtali Daggett, 1773 May 19 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - ALS Benjamin Lord to Naphtali Daggett, 1776 October 6 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - ALS Nehemiah Strong to the Corporation, 1776 October 23 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - ALS N. Daggett to the President and Fellows of Yale College Regarding his Resignation as President, 1777 April 3 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Richard Treat, ALS to Naphtali Daggett, 1777 April 5 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Alexander MacWhorter, ALS to Naphtali Daggett, thanking him for a degree, 1777 May 1 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Plans for Extending Education in Yale College Proposed to the Committee of the General Assembly, 1777-1778 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Oath of President Ezra Stiles, 1778 July 8 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - ALS L. Ely to the Corporation Regarding Acceptance of a Position, 1781 November 6 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Five Letters Regarding the Upstanding Character of Charles Mather Who Had Been Expelled in 1763, 1781 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Corporation Vote, 1782 January 11 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Fitch Ebenezer, Empowered by Yale College to Ask for Donations, 1783 March 28 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Corporation Votes, 1783 September 11 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Petition to the Yale Corporation to State Amount of Quarter Bills and How it was Spent, 1784 March 11 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Application for Honorary Degree for Mr. [Levi?] Hackley, 1786 September 7, 12 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Yale College Chapel List of Supply Pastors, 1786 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Corporation Appointment of Josiah Meigs as Lecturer, 1787 March 7 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Corporation Impowers John Salter as Their Attorney for the Salter Farm, 1787 May 22 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Petition to the General Assembly of Samuael Eells, 1787 May 22 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - ALS Daniel Everett to Rev. Judah Champion, 1787 September 1 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - ALS Sam Huntington to the Corporation Regarding a Bond for Payment, 1787 September 1 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Memorial to the General Assembly from Committee of the Corporation, 1787 September 14 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Memorial Regarding the President's House and Memorial Regarding Preemption of the Indian Lands at Scaticook, 1788 March 4 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Ezra Stiles, 1790 March 25? (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Price of Commons, 1790 May 26 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Dismissal Case of Elijah Waterman, 1791 March 8 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Regarding a Note, 1791 September 12 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Financial Report to the General Assembly by the Honors Committee, 1792 May 25 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Corporation "Approval of the Doings of the Legislature", 1792 June 26 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Corporation Empowerment of James Hillhouse, 1792 September 12 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Corporation Votes Regarding the Salter Farm, 1792 September 12 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Corporation Votes, 1793 May 12 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Building Location and Description, circa 1793 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - ALS J. Meigs Et. Al. to the Corporation Committee Regarding the Subordination of Classes Lower than Senior, 1795 August I8 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Declaration to the Committee of the Corporation Regarding the French Revolution by J. Meigs, 1798 September 13 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - ALS Josiah Meigs to the Corporation Regarding Retaining his Position at Yale After Being Publicly Charged as Being an Enemy of the United States, 1798 September 18 (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Corporation Votes, Circa 1799 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - ALS to the Corporation from the Selectmen of Warren [CT?] Regarding Land, 1799 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Committee Appointment, [179?] (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - A Reply to the Argument Against the Law of Yale College Obliging All the Students to Attend Worship on the Sabbath in College Hall, No Date (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Petition to the General Assembly Representation of Fellows of Yale College, [1796-1800?] (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence to Naphtali Daggett, 1755-1772 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Naphtali Daggett Documents [Gift of Williarn F. Hauemeyer of New York, 1901 March 10], 1749-1776 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Consent of Tutors J. Lyman, N. Parsons, J. Storrs, J. Chandler, S. Lee, E. White, A. Austin, D. Johnson, J. Howe, T. Dwight, J. Lewis, S. Williams, J. Lewis, N. Strong, J. Davenport, J. Buckminster, A. Baldwin, C. Goodrich, 1760-1779 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Consent of Tutors: E. Goodrich Jr., z. Ely. M. Russell, T. Chester, S. Baldwin, H.T. Chaming, E. Perkins, J. Morse, J, Denison, B. Bidwell, J. Whitney. D. Ely, N. Williams, R. Newton, 1780-1788 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Consent of Tutors: A. Basett, E. Gay, H. Ripley, C. Chapin, J. Edward; J. Meigs, 1779-1794 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Appointments of Tutors: Boardman, J. Lyma, J. Storrs, G. Griswold, E. White, Z. Ely, 1759-1781 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Resolved that Another Colligiate Building Was Needed, 1800 October [9] (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Report of the Prudential Committee to the Board of Trustees Regarding the Collection of Rents from College Lands, [1801?] September 2 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Records Management, 1801 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - ALS David Lawson to Governor Lawson, 1804 January 5; 1804 February (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - ALS Benjamin Silliman to Timothy Dwight, 1804 September 13 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - ALS Pliny Hillyer to the Hon. Lt. Governor Treadwell, 1807 March 9 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - ALS John Mix to the Corporation Concerning the Museum, 1807 September 11 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Expenses, 1807, 1822, 1829 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Museum Articles Loaned to John Mix, 1808 September 20 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Medical College Library Assignment, 1816 October 2 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - ALS Joseph Battell to Peter Starr, 1817 July 10 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Nathan Beers, Letter of Resignation, 1819 May 3 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - ALS J and L Gleason to the President of Yale College Regarding Steam Stoves, 1819 September 11 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - ALS Benjamin Silliman to Mrs. Humphreys Regarding a bust of Gen. Humphreys, 1820 September 13 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Petition for French, 1820 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Commencement: Excused for Non-Attendance, 1820-1821 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Eleazar T. Fitch, Memorial Presented to the First Church and Society in New Haven on the Call of N. W. Taylor to a Chair in the Yale Theological School, 1822 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Lists (Corporation), 1822-1846 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - ALS Signed Samuel F. Dickinson to the Corporation Concerning His Son's Tuition, 1823 September 5 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Monument for Fellow Student Class of 1823, 1824 September 4 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - ALS Abel W. Ewen to Rev. David Smith Regarding Yale College Church Subscription, 1824 January 26 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - ALS Archibald Barber to David Smith, 1824 December 23 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - [Chauncey?] Goodrich, Regarding a Year Leave of Absence, [1825?] (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Monument for Fellow Student, 1829 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Olmstead, Dennison. Reports to the Corporation Concerning a Telescope, other Apparatus, and an Observatory, [circa 1820's-1835] (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Jeremiah Day, Corporation, 1831 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Clark, Sheldon. Donation and Corporation Acceptance, 1832 March-April (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Kent Professorship of Law, 1832 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Centum Millia Fund, 1832 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - ALS A. [Tourinld?] to the Corporation, 1835 August 17 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Corporation, 1835 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Recommendation of Dr. Ralph Deming for Honorary Degree of Doctor of Medicine, 1837 July 25 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Corporation, 1839 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Memorandum Concerning Commons and Harvard and Brown Universities, [1830's?] (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - A Letter Sent by Jeremiah Day, 1840 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Judge Hitchcock Concerning the Fact that Yale Did Not Give a Degree in Law, 1842 August 6 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Resolution Regarding Death of Tutor John A. Dwight, 1843 October 24 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Corporation, 1843 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Law Graduates, 1843-1885 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Corporation, 1844 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Benjamin Silliman To the Corporation Regarding the Ledever Cabinet, 1845 August 5 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - ALS T. R. Strong to Rev. Edward Strong Regarding an Honorary Degree for Rev. Fisher, 1845 August 11 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Corporation, 1845 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Papers Regarding the Law Department and Law Library, Influenced by the Death of Judge Hitchcock, 1846 August (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Corporation, 1846 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - ALS L. Dwight Porter and Theodore W. Porter Regarding Gift of a Portrait of Timothy Dwight, Esq., 1846 August 4 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Jeremiah Day, Resignation of the Presidency, 1848 August 10 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Edward E. Salisbury, Three Letters with Reference to the Resignation of his Professorship in the Graduate Department., 1848 August 4 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Corporation, 1848 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Corporation, 1849 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Corporation: WM. J. Breed's statement, 1850 July (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Petition For an Increase of Law Library, 1850 August (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Corporation: De Forrest Fund, 1850-1852 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Corporation, 1851 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Corporation Vote Regarding Eleazar T. Fitch Resignation, 1852 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Corporation, 1852 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Corporation, 1853 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Chapel Organ Statement, 1853 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Corporation, 1854 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Corporation, 1855 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Communication of Committee of Students of the Gymnasium, 1856 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Corporation, 1856 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Plan of Gymnasium, 1856 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Corporation, 1857 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Papers Regarding the Gifts from Joseph E. Sheffield of Land and Buildings, 1858-1859 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Corporation, 1858 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Corporation, 1859 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Benjamin Silliman, Request for Purchase of Apparatus, 1860 July 12 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Corporation, 1860 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Corporation, Brothers and Linonian Societies, 1860 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Manuscript from Dr. Adolph Werner, Dessau, Germany. Cover Letter, 1860 January 27 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Petition to the President and Fellows from [?] Fitch Regarding Salary to Eleazar T. Fitch, 1861 July (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Corporation, 1861 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Doings of the President and Fellows of Yale College, 1862, 1863 July (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Trumball Gallery, 1862 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Eleazar T. Fitch, ALS to the Corporation, 1863 July 28 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Corporation, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Faculty of the Philosophy Department Concerning Candidates for Degrees, 1863-1866 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - ALS Benjamin Silliman to James Hadley Regarding Honorary Degree for John B. Harmon, 1864 June 18 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Corporation, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Osborne, Thomas B., Resignation, 1865 July 22 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Corporation, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Corporation, 1866 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Edward E. Salisbury, Letter to the Corporation on Removal of Paintings to the Yale Art School, 1866 June 21 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - ALS Chas F. Olney for an Honorary Degree from Himself, 1867 June 5 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - ALS N. Bouton Regarding Abraham N. Rubinson Receiving an Honorary Degree, 1867 July 2 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Corporation Meeting, 1867 July (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Corporation Meeting, 1868 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Corporation Meeting, 1869 July 20 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - List of People Invited to the Senior Dinner, 1870 June 29 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - William D. Whitney, Rules for the Ph.D. Degree, 1870 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Corporation, 1870 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Ten ALS Regarding Invitation to Noah Porter's Inauguration, 1871 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Regarding Porter Inauguration, 1871 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Regarding Porter Inauguration, 1871 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Recommendation on the Rules of Granting of the LLB Degree, 1871 October 26 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Kingsley Trust Association: John A. Porter Prize, 1871 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Thomas A. Thacher: Paper on Admission of Ph.D. Candidates Into Academic Department, 1871 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Corporation, 1871 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Thomas A. Thacher: Paper on the Reorganization of the Graduate Department, 1872 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - ALS ASA Tinker to the Corporation Regarding His Receiving an Honorary Degree, 1872? June 20 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Corporation, 1872 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Lyman H. Atwater, ALS of Thanks for Honorary Degree, 1873 June 30 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Corporation, 1873 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Fitch, L. W.: Petition for More Salary, 1873 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - ALS Theodore D. Woolsey Et. Al. Regarding a Bronze Medallion of W. H. Seward, 1874 January (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Corporation, 1874 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Boat Club, 1874 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Correspondence Regarding the Granting of a Certificate for I. Wilbur Perrott, Law Department, 1874-1875 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Law Faculty Memorial Regarding the Income of the English Fund, 1875 February 19 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Law Department Plan for Extending the Course of Study, 1875 June 15 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Corporation, 1875 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Corporation, 1876 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Robert W. Dale: 2 ALS of thanks for Honorary Degree, 1877 August 10 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Street Bequest, 1877 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Corporation, 1877 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Thacher Fund, Conditions of, 1877 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Recommendation of Theodore S. Woolsey to Professor of International Law, 1878 March 28 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - George W. Peabody, Letter to W. E. Bliss on his request for an Honorary Degree, 1878 May 28 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - ALS J. D. Park in Appreciation of His Honorary Degree, 1878 July 29 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Corporation, 1878 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Peabody Museum: Report of the Treasurer of the Trustees of the Museum, 1879 June 24 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Stoeckel, Gustave: Memorial Regarding the Battell Fund, 1879 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Corporation, 1879 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Francis Wayland: Letter to the Yale Corporation on Conditions of Law Degrees, 1880 June 26 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Thomas A. Thacher: Letter to the Yale Corporation, Respecting His Past Services, 1880 October 26 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Auditing Report, 1880 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - ALS to the Corporation Regarding "Yale Monumental Slab," Wrexham, No. Wales, 1881 April 4 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Vote by Law Faculty Regarding How Degrees May Be Granted, 1882 June 26 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Notification of the Resignation of Frederick H. Betts, 1884 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Corporation, 1884 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - ALS From F. Weir, D. G. Mitchell, W. K. Farnham, E. E. Salisbury to the Corporation Regarding Projected Positioning of the Christian Association Building, 1884 October 20 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Corporation, 1885 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Salisbury, Edward and Proposal for Endowment of Sanskrit Professorship, 1886 June (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Timothy Dwight Inauguration Letters
    - A, 1886 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - B, 1886 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - C, 1886 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - D, 1886 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - E-F, 1886 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - G, 1886 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - H, 1886 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - I-K, 1886 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - L, 1886 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - M, 1886 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - N-O, 1886 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - P, 1886 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - R, 1886 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - S, 1886 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - T-V, 1886 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - W, 1886 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Signature Illegible, 1886 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Corporation, 1887 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Welles, Cassius Scholarship, circa 1880's (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Corporation, 1890 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Corporation, 1894 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Corporation, No Date (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Treasurer's Duties, No Date (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Corporation Members: Connecticut State Senate, 1821-1870 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - The Hall Enquiry, 1818 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Petitions Regarding Commons, 1818-1832 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Letters Concerning the Stewardship of the Hall, 1819-1842 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Report Respecting the Hall (Commons), No Date (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Votes Regarding Commons, No Date (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Petitions for Honorary Degrees, 1830's-1880's (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Yale Church Papers Ecclesiastical Council Minutes Yale College Church, 1877-1893 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Yale Church Papers Ecclesiastical Council Regarding the Excommunication of Edward C. Towne. Two ALS Edward C. Towne., 1872, 1871 December (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Yale Church Papers Ecclesiastical Council Minutes Regarding William Barker Clarke's Installation as Pastor and Resignation Letters from WBC, 1863, 1866 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Yale Church Papers Ecclesiastical Council Minutes Regarding O. E. Daggett Resignation, 1870 September 27 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - OED Resignation, 1870 July 28 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Yale Church Papers Mimeographed Letter from Franklin B. Dexter Regarding Membership in the College Church, 1877 September 24 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Yale Church Papers Barbour, William Macleod and Seven ALS to Barbour, 1827-1899 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Yale Church Papers Letters Regarding Membership in the College Church
    - A-D, 1860's-1890's (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - E-N, 1860's-1890's (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - O-Z, 1860's-1890's (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Yale Church Papers
    - Certificates of Dismissal from Churches to Join the Church of Christ in Yale College, 1867-1894 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Enoch F. Burr, ALS Respecting His Membership in the Church in Yale College, 1877 September 26 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Oliver E. Daggett, ALS of Resignation Addressed to the College Church, 1870 September 6 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Daniel C. Gilman, Letter Respecting his Membership in the Yale College Church, 1877 November 10 (Box 4, Folder 57)